<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Products on Y.Wu</title>
    <link>/categories/products/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Products on Y.Wu</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Dec 2018 21:49:57 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/products/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>A Quantitative Study of the Iowa Population at the County Level</title>
      <link>/post/2018/12/07/a-quantitative-study-of-the-iowa-population-at-the-county-level/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Dec 2018 21:49:57 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018/12/07/a-quantitative-study-of-the-iowa-population-at-the-county-level/</guid>
      <description>Introduction The goal of this study is to look at:
 What is the relationships between the population and other variables, such as education attainment, poverty, the mean of income, and the median house value. Visually display the distribution of median house values across the state, and three frequency distributions based on the population of a county. All counties are evenly divided into three tiers:  Tier 1: population size from 3,000 to 11,000 (33 counties) Tier 2: population size form 11,000 to 20,000 (33 counties) Tier 3: population size form 20,000 to 48,200 (33 counties)  Correlations between:  Number of bechelor received and number of poverty.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Text Analysis-Python</title>
      <link>/post/2018/06/25/text-analysis-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jun 2018 21:49:57 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018/06/25/text-analysis-python/</guid>
      <description>This is a brief introduction to text analysis by using python. To be general, the processes are as follows:
 Set up correct working directory for importing document to process. Import .txt files in Python. Work towards the clean dataset as needed. Visualize data as requested.  There are many different ways to clean the dataset and alternate algorithms for text analysis. The following is the code along with some explaination of what I have learned for processing texts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Make Neighborhood Green Again</title>
      <link>/post/2018/04/20/make-neighborhood-green-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Apr 2018 21:49:57 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018/04/20/make-neighborhood-green-again/</guid>
      <description>West Lawrence Greening Project This is a story map made through https://storymaps.arcgis.com/en/. The story map demonstrates the lack of walkability and canopy in West Lawrence neighborhoods. More details can be found at https://www.arcgis.com/apps/Cascade/index.html?appid=21536c10fe15412aa449045c9c6b0444.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Combinatorial Proof of Binet&#39;s Formula</title>
      <link>/post/2017/12/01/a-combinatorial-proof-of-binets-formula/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 21:49:57 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2017/12/01/a-combinatorial-proof-of-binets-formula/</guid>
      <description>Binet’s Formula The Binet’s formula is also known as the explicit expression of n-th term of the Fibbonacci Sequence.
Brief Introduction Counting is a very basic skill. We have all been learning how to count since we were very young. If we think back to our childhood, other than simple vocabulary like “daddy” and “mommy”, the most common thing was to count the numbers from one to ten. In this case, counting could be the first exposure to mathematics for many people.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sample Time Series Analysis - Movie statistics</title>
      <link>/post/2016/04/20/sample-time-series-analysis---movie-statistics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2016/04/20/sample-time-series-analysis---movie-statistics/</guid>
      <description>Motivation Movies have been a source of entertainment for people for many years. Summertme superhero blockbusters typically bring excitement and fun to an otherwise calm tme. Theaters can rake in huge sums of money on these types of movies. In partcularr the movie Iron Man 3r released on May 3r 2013r provides a great example of this phenomenon. The box ofce tcket sales of this movie have been analyzed to ft the best tme series plot possible to atempt to approximate future movie tcket sales for movies of this type.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analysis of Housing Prices, Features Based Study  – Albuquerque, NM</title>
      <link>/post/2016/02/14/analysis-of-housing-prices-features-based-study---albuquerque-nm/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2016/02/14/analysis-of-housing-prices-features-based-study---albuquerque-nm/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Analyzing home prices is based on different factors that could affect the price of a house. Home prices may be affected by different factors such as square footage, age, number of features, location, etc. In this study, a dataset from Albuquerque was taken including square feet, age, number of certain features (out of 11, from dishwasher, refrigerator, microwave, disposer, washer, intercom, skylight(s), compactor, dryer, handicap fit, cable TV access), custom built or not, corner location or not, whether the home was located in the Northeast sector of the city, and its annual taxes.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>