<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Statistics on Y.Wu</title>
    <link>/tags/statistics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Statistics on Y.Wu</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Dec 2018 21:49:57 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/statistics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>A Quantitative Study of the Iowa Population at the County Level</title>
      <link>/post/2018/12/07/a-quantitative-study-of-the-iowa-population-at-the-county-level/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Dec 2018 21:49:57 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018/12/07/a-quantitative-study-of-the-iowa-population-at-the-county-level/</guid>
      <description>Introduction The goal of this study is to look at:
 What is the relationships between the population and other variables, such as education attainment, poverty, the mean of income, and the median house value. Visually display the distribution of median house values across the state, and three frequency distributions based on the population of a county. All counties are evenly divided into three tiers:  Tier 1: population size from 3,000 to 11,000 (33 counties) Tier 2: population size form 11,000 to 20,000 (33 counties) Tier 3: population size form 20,000 to 48,200 (33 counties)  Correlations between:  Number of bechelor received and number of poverty.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quantitative Terminologies</title>
      <link>/post/2018/09/23/quantitative-terminologies/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Sep 2018 21:49:57 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018/09/23/quantitative-terminologies/</guid>
      <description>A Random Blog From the Weekend Readings I would really love to have at least one blog posted at weekly basis. However, that is not likely to happen since life is hard, with no exception to myself. So, I have made this small goal of posting a blog of my readings from time to time. This week’s topic is about the quantitative terminology. In this blog, I will list definitions and terms that are very often used in statistics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sample Time Series Analysis - Movie statistics</title>
      <link>/post/2016/04/20/sample-time-series-analysis---movie-statistics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2016/04/20/sample-time-series-analysis---movie-statistics/</guid>
      <description>Motivation Movies have been a source of entertainment for people for many years. Summertme superhero blockbusters typically bring excitement and fun to an otherwise calm tme. Theaters can rake in huge sums of money on these types of movies. In partcularr the movie Iron Man 3r released on May 3r 2013r provides a great example of this phenomenon. The box ofce tcket sales of this movie have been analyzed to ft the best tme series plot possible to atempt to approximate future movie tcket sales for movies of this type.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analysis of Housing Prices, Features Based Study  – Albuquerque, NM</title>
      <link>/post/2016/02/14/analysis-of-housing-prices-features-based-study---albuquerque-nm/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2016/02/14/analysis-of-housing-prices-features-based-study---albuquerque-nm/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Analyzing home prices is based on different factors that could affect the price of a house. Home prices may be affected by different factors such as square footage, age, number of features, location, etc. In this study, a dataset from Albuquerque was taken including square feet, age, number of certain features (out of 11, from dishwasher, refrigerator, microwave, disposer, washer, intercom, skylight(s), compactor, dryer, handicap fit, cable TV access), custom built or not, corner location or not, whether the home was located in the Northeast sector of the city, and its annual taxes.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>